Register of the Fritz Machlup Papers, 1911-1983
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1911-1983.
  - "How I Decided to Become an Economist," 1977 May 22. Typewritten transcript of a speech (Folder 7)
  - Participation in panel discussion, The Existing Banking System: Will It Cope with Present-Day World-Wide Financing Requirements; Do We Have Alternatives? Compagnie Luxembourgeoise de la Dresdner Bank A.G., Kirchberg, Luxembourg, 1977 July 4
    - Printed copy (Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with Volker Burghagen and Jurgen Ponto. Includes typewritten transcript of Fritz Machlup's interventions, edited by him (Folder 9)
  - Statement on economic factors involved in royalty payment mechanisms, National Commission on New Technological Uses of Copyrighted Works (CONTU), 1977 July 11. Typescript (Folder 10)
  - Discussion of Gerhard Fels and Frank Weiss, "Structural Change and Unemployment: The Lesson of West Germany," Fifth World Congress of the International Economic Association, Tokyo, Japan, 1977 September 1. Printed copy (Folder 11)
  - Discussion of Janos Fekete, "Monetary and Financial Problems in East and West," Vienna Institute for Comparative Economic Studies and Institute for World Economics of the Hungarian Academy of Sciences, Workshop on East-West European Economic Interaction, Budapest, Hungary, 1977 October 17. Notes. Includes paper by Janos Fekete (Folder 12)
  - "An Amateurish Linguistic Exercise About the Japanese Language," 1978? Notes, typescript, and correspondence with Robert A. Fowkes (Folder 13)
  - Information Through the Printed Word: The Dissemination of Scholarly, Scientific, and Intellectual Knowledge (with Kenneth W. Leeson et al.), 1978-1980 (4 vols.).
    See also Knowledge: Its Creation, Distribution, and Economic Significance,1980-1983 (3 vols.)
    - General
      - Correspondence
        - General (Box 114, Folder 1)
        - Academic Press (Folder 2)
        - Association of American University Presses (Folder 3-7)
        - Carnegie Corporation of New York (Folder 8)
        - Elsevier Scientific Publishing Company (Folder 9)
        - Ford Foundation (Folder 10)
        - Institute for Scientific Information (Folder 11)
        - Leeson, Kenneth W. (Folder 12)
        - Lexington Books (Folder 13)
        - National Endowment for the Humanities (Folder 14)
        - National Science Foundation. Includes correspondence with New York University (Folder 15)
        - National Technical Information Service (Folder 16)
        - Plenum Publishing Corporation (Folder 17)
        - Praeger Publishers (Folder 18)
      - Financial records (Box 115, Folder 1-3)
      - Grant proposals (Folder 4-6)
      - Grant proposals (Box 116, Folder 1-2)
      - Personnel records (Folder 3-6)
      - Progress reports
        - 1976 June (Folder 7)
        - 1977 June (Folder 8)
      - Summary of entire project (Folder 9)
    - Research material
      - General (Folder 10-21)
      - General (Box 117, Folder 1-10)
      - Correspondence
        - General (Folder 11-15)
        - Requests
          - By Fritz Machlup (Folder 16)
          - By others (Folder 17)
        - American Council of Learned Societies (Folder 18)
        - American Library Association (Folder 19)
        - Association of American Publishers (Folder 20)
        - Association of Philosophy Journal Editors (Folder 21)
        - Association of Research Libraries (Folder 22)
        - Baumol, William J. (and Richard E. Quandt) (Box 118, Folder 1)
        - British Library (Folder 2)
        - Capital Systems Group (Folder 3)
        - Cline, Hugh F. (Folder 4)
        - Fry, Bernard M. (Folder 5)
        - Futures Group (Folder 6)
        - Kagann, Stephen E. (Folder 7-8)
        - Kagann, Stephen E. (Box 119, Folder 1-2)
        - Kent, Allen (Folder 3)
        - King Research (Folder 4)
        - King Research (Box 120, Folder 1)
        - National Commission on New Technological Uses of Copyrighted Works (Folder 2-3)
        - National Enquiry into Scholarly Communication (Folder 4)
        - New York State Geological Survey (Folder 5)
        - Pollard, Alan P. (Folder 6)
        - Primary Communications Research Centre (University of Leicester) (Folder 7)
        - Saracevic, Tefko (Folder 8)
        - United States Postmaster (Folder 9)
      - Data
        - Knowledge dissemination stages
          - Book publishing (Box 121, Folder 1-10)
          - Book (and journal) publishing (Box 122, Folder 1-11)
          - Journal publishing (Box 123, Folder 1-9)
          - Library services (Box 124, Folder 1-13)
          - Abstracting, indexing, reviewing (Box 125, Folder 1-11)
          - Reading (User studies) (Box 126, Folder 1-8)
        - Publishers
          - General (Box 127, Folder 1-4)
          - General (Box 128, Folder 1-2)
          - A-H (Folder 3-10)
          - J-R (Box 129, Folder 1-9)
          - S-Y (Box 130, Folder 1-6)
      - Memoranda (Folder 7)
      - Notes (Folder 8)
      - Questionnaires (Folder 9-11)
    - Typescript (Box 131, Folder 1-7)
    - Typescript (Box 132, Folder 1-14)
    - Typescript (Box 133, Folder 1-18)
    - Typescript (Box 134, Folder 1-5)
    - Proofs (Folder 6)
    - Proofs (Box 135, Folder 1-2)
    - Proofs (Box 136, Folder 1-3)
    - Proofs (Box 137, Folder 1-2)
    - Reviews (Folder 3)
  - Methodology of Economics and Other Social Sciences, 1978
    - Typescript
      - Outline of book (Box 138, Folder 1)
      - Outline of "Ideal Types, Reality, and Construction." Includes notes and English translation (by Martha De Rooy) of "Idealtypus, Wirklichkeit und Konstruktion," annotated and with holograph preface by Fritz Machlup, and correspondence, 1977 (Folder 2)
      - Note on Spiro J. Latsis, 1977 July (Folder 3)
    - Printed copies of the component writings (Folder 4)
    - Reviews (Folder 5)
  - "The Changing Structure of the Knowledge-Producing Labor Force" (with Stephen E. Kagann), 1978 January
    - Typescript (Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Bell Journal of Economics, Economic Inquiry, Journal of Human Resources, and Noordhoff International (Folder 7)
  - "Die Tragodie der wirtschaftspolitischen Illusionen," 1978 February 14. Speech, Creditanstalt-Bankverein, Vienna, Austria. Typescript and correspondence (Folder 8)
  - "Research Highlight: The Dissemination of Scholarly Knowledge," Center for Applied Economics Newsletter, 1978 April and June (Parts 1 and 2). Printed copy (Folder 9)
  - Opening remarks, Conference on the 'Locomotive Theory,' American Enterprise Institute, Washington, D.C., 1978 April 13. Notes and typescript (Folder 10)
  - "The Development of the Austrian Economy Since the Second World War," 1978 May 19. Speech, Center for Austrian Studies, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis. Typescript, printed copy, and correspondence with William E. Wright (Folder 11)
  - Review of Mark Perlman, ed., The Organization and Retrieval of Economic Knowledge: Proceedings of a Conference Held by the International Economic Association at Kiel, West Germany, in Economic Journal, 1978 June. Printed copy (Folder 12)
  - "Youth Unemployment, Minimum Wage, and the Proportion of Inexperienced Workers in the Labor Force," 1978 June. Typescript and correspondence (Folder 13)
  - "An Economist's Reflections on an Institute for the Advanced Study of Information Science," 1978 August 1-11. Paper, Advanced Study Institute of Information Science, Chania, Crete
    - General (Folder 14)
    - Notes (Folder 15)
    - Typescript of revised version and printed copy (Folder 16)
    - Correspondence with Anthony Debons, Arvid G. Larson, J. C. R. Licklider, Charles T. Meadow (Journal of the American Society for Information Science), R. K. Stamper, Helmut E. Thiess (Folder 17)
  - Series of four speeches, Bolsa de Comercio de Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1978 September 11-14
    - Printed copy (Folder 18)
    - Clippings (Folder 19)
    - Correspondence with Alberto Guido Servente, Jose Heriberto Martinez, and Julio H. G. Olivera. Includes typewritten introduction of Fritz Machlup by Julio H. G. Olivera (Folder 20)
  - Discussion of "Worries and Priorities," "The Present International Monetary System," "The Experience with Managed Floating," and "The SDR and Other IMF Matters," Claremont International Monetary Conference, Claremont, California, 1978 October 3-6. Typescript, clippings, and correspondence with Randall B. Hinshaw (Folder 21)
  - "A Recipe for a Good Graduate Department," The Chronicle of Higher Education, 1978 October 16. Printed copy and comments (Folder 22)
  - "Inflation and Unemployment," 1978 November 7. William L. Clayton Lecture on International Economic Affairs, Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy, Tufts University, Medford, Massachusetts. Printed copies, including under the title "Different Inflations Have Different Effects on Unemployment," Banca Nazionale del Lavoro Quarterly Review, 1978 December (Folder 23)
  - "The Effects of Fiscal Policy and the Choice of Definitions," in Harry I. Greenfield et al., eds., Theory for Economic Efficiency: Essays in Honor of Abba P. Lerner, 1979. Printed copy (Box 139, Folder 1)
  - "Hayek, Friedrich A. von," in David L. Sills, ed., International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1979
    - General (Folder 2)
    - Research material and notes (Folder 3)
    - Typescript (Folder 4-5)
    - Printed copy (Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Barbara A. Chernow (Free Press) (Folder 7)
  - Kyoiku no Genso (Illusion of Education), 1979. Typescript preface and correspondence with Hiroshi Kida and Seisuke Komatsuzaki. Includes notes and tables on the knowledge industry (Folder 8)
  - "The Semantics of Science," 1979. Typescript and correspondence (Folder 9)
  - "The EMS, the Odds for Stability, the U.S. Dollar, and the IMF," Aussenwirtschaft, 1979 March. Printed copy (Folder 10)
  - "Economics as Seen by Myself as a Researcher, Writer, Teacher, Government Advisor, Businessman, Citizen, and Philosopher" ("As I Have Looked at Economics in My Various Roles"), 1979 March 13. Speech, Seminar in Economic Issues, Graduate Economics Society, New York University, New York City. Notes and typewritten transcript (Folder 11)
  - Discussion of the papers by John H. Williamson and Alexandre Lamfalussy, Louvain-La-Neuve, Belgium, 1979 March 24. Typescript (Folder 12)
  - "International Adjustments and Coordination of Monetary Policies," 1979 May 2. Speech, Metropolitan Economic Association, New York City. Typewritten outline and correspondence (Folder 13)
  - "Uses, Value, and Benefits of Knowledge," Knowledge: Creation, Diffusion, Utilization, 1979 September. Printed copy (Folder 14)
  - "Poor Learning from Good Teachers," Academe, 1979 October. Printed copy of condensed version and comments (Folder 15)
  - "Erinnerungen an das Mises-Seminar," 1979 October 24. Notes and typescript (Folder 16)
  - "An Experiment Testing the Findings of Econometric Research Techniques," 1979 November 10. Typescript (Folder 17)
  - "The Economic Cost of Knowledge," in Emil Kung, ed., Wandlungen in Wirtschaft und Gesellschaft, Festschrift fur Walter Adolf Johr, 1980. Printed copy (Folder 18)
  - "Explaining Changes in Balances of Payments and Foreign Exchange Rates: A Polemic without Graphs, Algebra, and Citations," in John S. Chipman and Charles P. Kindleberger, eds., Flexible Exchange Rates and the Balance of Payments, 1980. Printed copy (Folder 19)
  - Foreword to Jacques Riboud, The Mechanics of Money, 1980
    - Miscellany (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - Typescript of book manuscript (Folder 2-4)
    - Printed copy (Folder 5)
  - Knowledge: Its Creation, Distribution, and Economic Significance, 1980-1983 (3 vols.)
    - General
      - Correspondence.
        See also Financial records
        - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation (Box 141, Folder 1-2)
        - Esther A. and Joseph Klingenstein Fund (Folder 3)
        - Exxon Education Foundation (Folder 4)
        - Ford Foundation (Folder 5)
        - Institute for Educational Affairs (Folder 6)
        - International Business Machines Corporation. Includes correspondence with Carl Rieser (Folder 7)
        - John and Mary Markle Foundation (Folder 8)
        - Miscellaneous (Folder 9)
        - National Endowment for the Humanities (Folder 10)
        - National Institute of Education (Box 142, Folder 1-3)
        - National Science Foundation (Folder 4-5)
        - Princeton University (Folder 6)
        - Princeton University Press (Folder 7)
        - Smith Richardson Foundation (Box 143, Folder 1)
        - Spencer Foundation (Folder 2)
        - System Development Foundation (Folder 3)
      - Financial records (Folder 4-12)
      - Lists
        - Grants supporting the project (Folder 13)
        - Materials for possible use in final report (Folder 14)
      - Memorandum on cataloging of the final work (Folder 15)
      - Research assistant records, including for Barbara A. Chernow and Stephen E. Kagann (Box 144, Folder 1-49)
    - Research material. Includes notes and correspondence
      - General. Includes correspondence with King Research (Box 145, Folder 1-13)
      - Volume I (Box 146, Folder 1-2)
      - Volume II (Folder 3-9)
      - Volume III (Folder 147-153)
      - Volume IV (Folder 154)
      - Volume V (Folder 155-191)
      - Volume VI (Folder 192-200)
      - Volume VII (Folder 201-202)
      - Volume VIII (Folder 203-205)
      - Volume X (Folder 205)
    - Notes (Folder 206)
    - Typescript
      - Outlines (Box 207, Folder 1-7)
      - Volume I (Folder 8-10)
      - Volume II (Folder 11)
      - Volume II (Box 208, Folder 1-5)
      - Volume III (Box 209, Folder 1-4)
      - Volume III (Box 210, Folder 1-5)
      - Volume III (Box 211, Folder 1-2)
      - Volume IV (Folder 3)
    - Readers' comments - Volume III (Folder 4-8)
    - Proofs
      - Volume I (Box 212, Folder 1-3)
      - Volume II (Folder 4-7)
    - Production schedule - Volume III (Box 213, Folder 1)
    - Promotional material
      - Volumes I and II (Folder 2)
      - Volume III (Folder 3)
    - Distribution lists (Folder 4-7)
    - Reviews (Folder 8)
    - Correspondence
      - Volume I (Folder 9)
      - Volume II (Folder 10)
      - Volume III (Folder 11-13)
      - Volume IV.
        See also The Study of Information: Interdisciplinary Messages, 1983
        - General - Advisors
          - Academicians (Box 214, Folder 1)
          - Consultants (Folder 2)
        - Ackoff, Russell L. (Folder 3)
        - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation (Folder 4)
        - Arbib, Michael A. (Folder 5)
        - Barr, Avron (Folder 6)
        - Batty, David (Folder 7)
        - Baumol, William J. (Folder 8)
        - Beam, Robert D. (Folder 9)
        - Bearman, Toni Carbo (Folder 10)
        - Beniger, James R. (Folder 11)
        - Berwick, Robert C. (Folder 12)
        - Bever, Thomas G. (Box 215, Folder 1)
        - Boden, Margaret A. (Folder 2)
        - Boulding, Kenneth E. (Folder 3)
        - Brown, John Seely (Folder 4)
        - Buckley, Walter (Folder 5)
        - Cherry, Heather (Folder 6)
        - Churchman, C. West (Folder 7)
        - Day, Richard H. (Folder 8)
        - Debons, Anthony (Folder 9)
        - Donelson, William C. (Folder 10)
        - Dougherty, Ray Cordell (Folder 11)
        - Ebenfield, Helene (Folder 12)
        - Eden, Murray (Folder 13)
        - Elias, Peter (Box 216, Folder 1)
        - Garfield, Eugene (Folder 2)
        - Gazzaniga, Michael S. (Folder 3)
        - Gorelik, George (Folder 4)
        - Gorn, Saul (Folder 5)
        - Griffith, Belver C. (Folder 6)
        - Hewitt, Carl E. (Folder 7)
        - Hofstadter, Douglas R. (Folder 8)
        - Kalman, Rudolf E. (Folder 9)
        - Keyser, Samuel Jay (Folder 10)
        - Knuth, Donald Ervin (Folder 11)
        - Kochen, Manfred (Folder 12)
        - Langlois, Richard N. (Box 217, Folder 1)
        - Lewis, Ralph W. (Folder 2)
        - Licklider, J. C. R. (Folder 3)
        - MacKay, Donald MacCrimmon (Folder 4)
        - Marcus, Mitchell (Folder 5)
        - Mattessich, Richard (Folder 6)
        - Mead, Carver (Folder 7)
        - Melnechuk, Theodore (Folder 8)
        - Michon, John A. (Folder 9)
        - Miller, George Armitage (Folder 10)
        - Minsky, Marvin L. (Folder 11)
        - Montroll, Elliott W. (Box 218, Folder 1)
        - Mortazavian, Hassan (and Mihajlo D. Mesarovic) (Folder 2)
        - Moses, Joel (Folder 3)
        - Negroponte, Nicolas (Folder 4)
        - Newell, Allen (Folder 5)
        - Nilsson, Nils (Folder 6)
        - Norman, Donald A. (Folder 7)
        - Parker, Edwin B. (Folder 8)
        - Perlis, Alan J. (Folder 9)
        - Pylyshyn, Zenon W. (Folder 10)
        - Rayward, W. Boyd (Folder 11)
        - Rich, Robert F. (Box 219, Folder 1)
        - Schrader, Alvin M. (Folder 2)
        - Shapiro, Michael M. (Folder 3)
        - Shannon, Claude E. (Folder 4)
        - Simon, Herb A. (Folder 5)
        - Shera, Jesse Hauk (Folder 6)
        - Slamecka, Vladimir (Folder 7)
        - Slepian, David (Folder 8)
        - Steiglitz, Kenneth (Folder 9)
        - Swanson, Don R. (Folder 10)
        - Swire, Peter (Folder 11)
        - Taylor, Howard F. (Folder 12)
        - Tribus, Myron (Folder 13)
        - Tversky, Amos (Folder 14)
        - Wegner, Peter (Folder 15)
        - Wellisch, Hans (Folder 16)
        - Wilson, Patrick (Folder 17)
        - Winograd, Terry (Folder 18)
        - Wooster, Harold (Folder 19)
        - Wyner, Aaaron D. (Folder 20)
        - Zwass, Vladimir (Folder 21)
  - "The Scientific Status of Information Science," 1980. Typescript (Box 220, Folder 1)
  - "Theorien uber die Bestimmung der Wechselkurse," 1980. Draft for a possible speech or article. Holograph (Folder 2)
  - "Commentary: The Outlook for the Dollar and Other International Assets," 1980 February 29. Discussion of the papers by Edward M. Bernstein and Michele Fratiani, Conference on the International Monetary System under Stress, American Enterprise Institute for Public Policy Research, Washington, D.C. Typescript and printed copy (Folder 3)
  - "Wirtschaftspolitik: Musterbeispiel Osterreich," 1980 May 13. Paper, Auslandsosterreicher-Symposium anlasslich des 25. Jahrestages der Unterzeichnung des Osterreichischen Staatsvertrages, Vienna, Austria
    - General. Includes papers by others (Folder 4)
    - Research material and notes (Folder 5)
    - Typescript and printed copy (Folder 6)
    - Correspondence
      - Auslandsosterreicherwerk (Fritz Molden) (Folder 7)
      - Erste-Wirtschaftsanalysen (Folder 8)
      - "Projekt 25 Jahre Staatsvertrag" (Folder 9)
  - "An Interview with Professor Fritz Machlup," Austrian Economics Newsletter, 1980 Summer. Printed copy (Folder 10)
  - "My Early Work on International Monetary Problems," Banca Nazionale del Lavoro Quarterly Review, 1980 June
    - Research material (Folder 11)
    - Holograph (Folder 12)
    - Typescript (Folder 13-14)
    - Printed copy (Folder 15)
    - German translation
      - Typescript and printed copy (Folder 16)
      - Correspondence with Karl Acham (Folder 17)
  - Paper, Conference for Information Science, Evanston, Illinois, 1980 November 6-8. List of topics, glossary, and notes (Folder 18)
  - "My Ongoing Research on Knowledge and Knowledge Production," 1981 February 19. Speech, National Science Foundation Seminar, Washington, D.C. Notes (Box 221, Folder 1)
  - "Knowledge Information and the Economy," 1981 February 26. Speech, Tallahas (Folder 2)
    see, Florida. Notes
  - "Ludwig von Mises: A Scholar Who Would Not Compromise," 1981 September 10. Speech, Ludwig von Mises Centenary, Hillsdale College, Hillsdale, Michigan
    - Notes (Folder 3)
    - Typescript (Folder 4)
    - Printed copy (Folder 5)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 6)
      - Trowbridge, Ronald L. (Folder 7)
      - Wirtschaftspolitische Blatter (Meinhard Supper) (Folder 8)
  - "Sciences of Information: Looking Over the Fences," 1981 October 25-30. Paper, American Society for Information Science, Washington, D.C. Notes, typewritten abstract, and correspondence, including with Lois F. Lunin (Folder 9)
  - "Ten Speeches Rolled into One," 1981 November 6. Address, Academy of Independent Scholars, Symposium on the Optimum Utilization of Knowledge, University of Massachusetts, Amherst
    - General (Folder 10)
    - Notes (Folder 11)
    - Typewritten transcript, partially edited by Fritz Machlup (Folder 12)
    - Correspondence with Vicki Holzhauer and Lawrence Senesh. Includes edited typescript of speech given on January 8, 1982, "What Do We Mean by Optimum Utilization of Knowledge?" which was eventually used for the publication of the Amherst proceedings (Folder 13)
  - "The World Monetary Order," 1981 November 18. Speech, State Bank of Pakistan, Karachi, Pakistan
    - General (Folder 14)
    - Research material and notes, including on India and Nepal (Folder 15)
    - Typescript and printed matter (Folder 16)
    - Correspondence with Gerald E. Bouchoux (International Communications Agency), S. Aijaz Husain, A. G. N. Kazi (Folder 17)
    - Clippings (Folder 18)
  - "The Theory of Human Capital," 1981 November 21. Speech, Pakistan Institute of Development Economics, Islamabad
    - Notes (Folder 19)
    - Holograph (in part typescript) (Folder 20)
    - Typescript (Folder 21)
    - Printed copy (Folder 22)
  - "International Monetary Issues," 1981 November 22. Speech, Pakistan Institute of Development Economics, Islamabad, Pakistan
    - Typescript and correspondence (Box 222, Folder 1)
    - Clipping (relating to both speeches at the Institute) (Folder 2)
  - "Von wirtschaftlichem Schwindel befreien: Fuhrer durch die Krisenpolitik - Ein fiktives Interview mit Professor Fritz Machlup," Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung, 1981 December 24. Typescript, printed copy, and correspondence with Rudiger Soltwedel (Folder 3)
  - "Austrian Economics," in Douglas Greenwald, ed., Encyclopedia of Economics, 1982
    - Research material and notes (Folder 4)
    - Typescript and printed copy (Folder 5)
  - "Beruhazasok az emberi eroforrasokba es a produktiv tudasba" (Investment in Human Resources and Productive Knowledge), in Adam Schmidt and Egon Kemenes, eds., Valtozasok, Valtasok es Valsagok a Gazdasagban: Tanulmanyok Varga Istvan emlekezetere, 1982. Printed copy (Folder 6)
  - "Growth Rates, Trade Balances, and Exchange Rates," in Richard N. Cooper, Peter B. Kenen, Jorge Braga de Macedo and Jacques van Ypersele, eds., The International Monetary Systems Under Flexible Exchange Rates, Global, Regional, and National: Essays in Honor of Robert Triffin, 1982. Proofs and printed copy (Folder 7)
  - "Marginal Revenue," in Douglas Greenwald, ed., Encyclopedia of Economics, 1982. Printed copy (Folder 8)
  - "What Do We Mean by Optimum Utilization of Knowledge?" 1982 January 8. Speech, Academy of Independent Scholars Symposium (held at the annual meeting of the American Association for the Advancement of Sciences), Boulder, Colorado
    - Research material and notes (Folder 9)
    - Typescript (Folder 10)
    - Printed copy ("Optimum Utilization of Knowledge") (Folder 11)
    - Correspondence
      - Academy of Independent Scholars (Folder 12)
      - Transaction/Society (Karen Osborne, Irving Louis Horowitz) (Folder 13)
  - "My Work on International Monetary Problems, 1940-1964," Banca Nazionale del Lavoro Quarterly Review, 1982 March
    - Typescript (Folder 14)
    - Printed copy (Folder 15)
    - German translation, "Wahrungsprobleme der Zwischenkriegszeit." Printed copy (Folder 16)
  - "Abolishment of All Import Barriers," The Questionnaire Survey on Japan's Role in the World, 1982 April. Typewritten answers to two questions by the Tokyo Colloquium (Folder 17)
  - Notes on the U.S. economic recovery, 1982 April 17. Holograph (Folder 18)
  - Letter to the editor, Science, 1982 December 3 (date written). Typescript (Folder 19)